Alexandre Odoni

Full Stack Developer

Full Software Lifecycle • Agile Development Practice • Enterprise Development

Personal Summary

A qualified and highly experienced technical developer with over 20 years commercial experience particularly in the online industry. During this period I have also gained valuable experience in leading development teams. I have both technical and interpersonal skills and am looking for a challenging role that utilises my previous skills and experiences. I want to contribute as much as possible and create great software and be part of the most innovative company.

Technical Skills

	Technologies		Databases	Operating Systems		Other Technologies	
+	React	+	SQL Server	+	Linux	+	Jest
+	React Native	+	PostgreSQL	+	Ubuntu	+	HTML
+	NextJS	+	MySQL	+	Debian	+	PHP
+	AdonisJS	+	MongoDB	+	UNIX	+	Shell Script
+	Java,J2EE,J2SE	+	Oracle 9/10/11	+	Windows	+	CMS (Magnolia)
+	Struts	+	RBDMS			+	Supervisor
+	Spring					+	Gunicorn
+	Hibernate					+	Celery
+	Ajax					+	
+	Django					+	Agile Methodologies Continuous
+	Python					,	Integration
+	Vue					+	Git
+	Express						
+	BlitzJS						

Professional Experience

Câmara Municipal de Curitiba 2011 – Present Full Stack Developer

⁺I am the main responsible for create applications using many NodeJS stacks like NextJS, React, React Native, Express, Adonis, NestJS.

- +I am responsible for develop the new projects for the company from the requirements gathering through deploying as well manage the developing environment for the team.
- +It was my responsability to gather the requirements for the new projects, create and manage the tasks on GitHub.
- +It was my responsability to develop the backend code for the project, most of them using Django Rest Framework.
- +It was my responsability to develop the frontend code for the project, some of them using Django and Bootstrap, some of them using Vue and some of them using React.
- + It was my responsability to create all the tests for the projects, from unit tests to integration tests.
- +It was my responsability to set up the Continuous Integration environment using TravisCI and integrate with the deploy scripts.
- +It was my responsability create all deploy scripts for the projects and integrate them with CI servers.
- +It was my responsability to develop reusable components in Django, for example, the authentication module which was used by all systems to authenticate through LDAP server.
- **→** Team size : 10 developers.
- + Projects: Sistema de Chamados (Internal Follow Up System), Sistema de Votação (Voting System), Sistema de Ramais (Extensions System), Sistema de Calendário (Calendar System), Sistema de Almoxarifado (Storeroom System), Sistema de Proposições Legislativas (Legislative Propositions System), Portal da Transparência (Transparency Portal).

Technologies used: Python, Django, Django Rest Framework, React, Vue, Node, Webpack, Axios, responsive frameworks (Bootstrap, Material Design), ES6, TypeScript, Shell Script

HSBC GLTb 2007-2011 Software Developer

I was part of a big team of analysts and developers who worked on many HSBC projects around the world. We attended meetings with different customers from Canada, China, USA, England, Mexico and India. Our tasks included developing specific parts of large projects. I also was allocated for 8 months to work as on-site coordinator in Vancouver, Canadá to help the HSBC Canada team in many projects.

- + It was my responsability do attend meetings, gather requirements and create tasks for the team.
- + It was my responsability to develop front end code for the projects.
- + It was my responsability to manage the tasks and provide feedback to the customers.
- +The front end team consisted of approximately 200 members
- + The back end team consisted of approximately 150 members;
- + Projects: Credit card, Updating Java servers (Weblogic), many other parts of large projects.

Technologies used: Java, Spring, Internal HSBC Framework, HTML, CSS, MQueue, Struts

EDS - Electronic Data Systems 2002-2007 Software Developer

I was part of a big team of analysts and developers who worked in many outsourcing projects for EDS.

+It was my responsibility to attend meetings with other members of the team and discuss and manage

solutions for the problems.

- +It was my responsability to create and manage the tasks.
- +It was my responsability to code the front end code for the large projects and the front and back end code for the medium and small projects.
- + The front end team consisted of approximately 100 members.
- + The back end team consisted of approximately 100 members.
- + The biggest project I worked was the Visanet project which was responsible to manage the transactions of this card. I worked in many other projects also.

Technologies used: Java, Spring, Oracle, MSSQL Server, Struts, MVC Frameworks.

Education

1991-1995 Pontificia Universidade Católica do Paraná Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

2020-2021 MBA Software Engineering FAMEESP - Faculdade Metropolitana do Estado de São Paulo

Other

I'm a fan of new technologies, always learning new languages, frameworks, etc. I'm also very fan of developing apps for mobile. I'm autodidact and it's easy to me learn new things.

I also contribute for many projects in GitHub and almost all my personal projects are published there.

I have many hobbies like cooking, woodworking, running, cycling, traveling, kayaking, playing guitar and having fun with friends.